Guide to the L. Jackson Newell Audio-Visual Collection 1964-2012
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
L. Jackson Newell Audio Visual Collection
1964-2012
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 801-581-8864 http://www.lib.utah.edu/collections/multimedia-archives/
A0927
L. Jackson Newell
206 audiocassettes, 79 DVD, 42 VHS videocassette, 19 compact disc, 31 Super 8mm film, 7 8mm film, 7 microcassette, 1 minicassette, 3 floppy discs, 5 mini floppy disc, 1 U-matic videocassette
This collection contains the professional and personal history of L. Jackson Newell. Many of these items contain interviews between Newell and his collegues at the University of Utah and Deep Spring Colleges.
Biographical Note
s an avid student, L. Jackson Newell has pursued a lifelong committed journey to social ethics and educational philosophies. Beginning with his master’s degree at Duke University, Newell has studied the history and philosophy of colleges and university. He received his M.A. in American and European history followed by his doctorate in the history and philosophy of American and European universities. His education was only the beginning of his involvement in the world of study.
Starting in 1974, Newell played a key role at the University of Utah by designing a liberal arts and science program that spanned the campus. His involvement with the Liberal Education Program created a national acclaim because of its interdisciplinary nature and creativity in many aspects of the program. Until 1990, Newell was involved with this program, launching two professorships, the McMurrin Professorship for visiting scholars and the University Professorship for the University of Utah faculty. The McMurrin Professorship, endowed by O.C. Tanner in 1980, was created in the name of Professor McMurrin, a prominent figure at the University of Utah. This professorship brings a scholar of recognized stature to enrich education and discourse.
After leaving the University of Utah, Newell, soon after, became a part of Deep Springs, a two year undergraduate college in California. Having completed his undergraduate here, he became involved during a time of struggle at the college to revitalize the once strong school. Deep Springs is noted for its strong community ties that intertwine education and hard work. Founded by L.L. Nunn, a person of interest for Newell, the school was built on the three pillars of academics, labor, and self-governance. As a part of this community, Newell helped reestablish the strong ties to education through financial stability and renovation of college.
Beyond his teaching career, L. Jackson Newell has been a part of multiple voluntary organizations. He worked with the Bennion Center for Community Service as well as acted as an advisor for academic leaders at universities worldwide. He has won awards such as the Deep Springs Medal for exemplary service to humanity, the Joseph Katz award for the Advancement of Learning, the Hatch Prize for Teaching and the Distinguished Honors Professor Award at the University of Utah. Among his many awards for teaching and volunteering, Newell has also published a multitude of written works on education including a biographical study of Sterling McMurrin, the above named professor. In Matters of Conscience: Conversations with Sterling McMurrin on Philosophy, Education, and Religion, he explores Sterling McMurrin as United States Commissioner of Education during John F. Kennedy’s presidency. L. Jackson Newell has provided a large amount of work to the world over the years through his volunteering efforts, his teaching valor, and his written word.
Currently, Newell is Professor Emeritus at the University of Utah and President Emeritus at Deep Springs College. He also serves on the boards for the Utah Humanities Council, the Tanner Lectures on Human Values, the McMurrin Lectures, and the Virgin River Land Preservation Association. His commitment to his community and education has left a collection of various audio visual artifacts that speak to the magnitude of work he has done during his career in education leadership.
More information on L. Jackson Newell can be found on his website.
Arranged by order in box.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
Donated by L. Jackson Newell in 2014.
See the Guide to Jackson Newell Papers 1964-1990
See the Inventory of Sterling M. McMurrin Papers 1830-2006
L. Jackson Newell;;; Deep Springs College; Education; Colleges and Universities; Utah; California; Moving Images; Sound Recordings; Moving images; Sound recordings
- Frank Newman at Utah, 04 December 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 1)
  Master 1
- Frank Newman at Utah, 04 December 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 2)
  Master 2
- Frank Newman at Utah, 04 December 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 3)
- Frank Newman at Utah, 04 December 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 4)
- Ernest Benjamin, 01 October 1988; Audiocassette (Cassette 5)
- Values and General Education: A Integrated Approach, 1988; Audiocassette (Cassette 6)
  1988 National Conference on Higher Education
- Strategies a Chairperson Can Use to Improve Teaching Affectiveness, 1988; Audiocassette (Cassette 7)
- A National Survey of TA Training, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 8)
  2nd National Conference on Training and Employment of TAs
- Three Levels of TA Training: Univ.-Wide, Discipline-Specific, and Within a Course, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 9)
- Satellite Colleges: Lessons from Undergraduate Experiments to the 60's 70's, 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 10)
  1985 National Conference on Higher Education-Chicago
- Events in the People's Republic of China: Policy Implications for TA's and Their Hosts, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 11)
  2nd National Conference on Training and Employment of TA's
- Models of Mentoring and Peer Consultaion, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 12)
- Prerequisite for Common Learning: An Uncommon Faculty, 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 13)
- Developing Skills and Reflective Practices: Exploring New Research for Administrators, 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 14)
- Learing to Meditate by P. Carrington-Introduction, undate; Audiocassette (Cassette 15)
- Learning to Meditate: Instruction in Mediation and Post Instruction, undate; Audiocassette (Cassette 16)
- Learing to Meditate 2nd and 9th Day, undate; Audiocassette (Cassette 17)
- Herbert C. Kelman Lecture 1, 13 November 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 18)
- Herbert C. Kelman Lecture 2, 13 November 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 19)
- Herbert C. Kelman Lecture 2, 13 November 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 20)
- Darwin Lecture 3, 01 March 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 21)
  Evolution and Development, Bonner
- Darwin Lecture 3, 01 March 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 22)
- Darwin Lecture 4, 11 March 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 23)
  Natural Selection, A.J. Cain
- Darwin Lecture 5, 08 April 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 24)
  Freud and Evolutionary Biology, F.Sulloway
- Darwin Lecture 7, 08 April 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 25)
  Charles Darwin and Communication, J.Campbell
- Darwin Lecture 7, 27 April 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 26)
  Charles Darwing and Communication, J.Campbell
- Darwin Lecture 7, 27 April 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 27)
- The Darwin Revoltion, Lecture 1, 04 February 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 28)
  Chiselin1
- Darwin Lecture 9, 02 May 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 29)
  Evolution and Creation: Two World Views, C.Davern
- Darwin Lecture 9, 02 May 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 30)
- Professor Forum: The Politics of Extremism, April 1981; Audiocassette (Cassette 31)
  Canning
- Professor Forum: The Politics of Extremism, April 1981; Audiocassette (Cassette 32)
- Professor Forum: Public Education-What Should Be Done, 06 April 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 33)
- Professor Forum: Public Education-What Should Be Done, 06 April 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 34)
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 02 May 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 35)
  1/1A
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 02 May 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 36)
  2/2A/2B
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 37)
  3/3A/3B
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 04 June 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 38)
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 21 June 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 39)
  5/5A/5B
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 21 June 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 40)
  5 Continued
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 15 August 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 41)
  6/6A/6B
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 05 September 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 42)
  7/7A/7B
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 13 September 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 43)
  8/8A/8B
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, September 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 44)
  9/9A/9B
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 10 October 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 45)
  10/10A/10B
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 19 December 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 46)
  11/11A/11B
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 09 January 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 47)
  12/12A/12B
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, January 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 48)
  13/13A/13B
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 13 August 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 49)
  14/14A/14B
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 15 August 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 50)
  Conversation 2: Tape 15
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 13 August 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 51)
  Conversation 3: Tape 16
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 13 August 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 52)
  Conversation 4: Tape 17
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 09 October 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 53)
  Conversation 5: Tape 18
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 15 October 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 54)
  Conversation 6: Tape 19
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 22 October 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 55)
  Conversation 7: Tape 20
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 05 November 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 56)
  Conversation 8: Tape 21
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 12 November 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 57)
  Conversation 9: Tape 22
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 26 November 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 58)
  Conversation 10: Tape 23
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 30 January 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 59)
  Conversation 11: Tape 24
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 60)
  Conversation 12: Tape 25
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 25 February 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 61)
  Conversation 13: Tape 26
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 62)
  Conversation 14: Tape 27
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 17 March 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 63)
  Conversation 15: Tape 28
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 64)
  Conversation 16: Tape 29
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 65)
  Conversation 17: Tape 30
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 13 May 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 66)
  Conversation 18: Tape 31
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 19 May 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 67)
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 27 May 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 68)
  Conversation 20: Academic Freedom
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 12 June 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 69)
  Conversation 21
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 18 June 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 70)
  Conversation 22
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 08 September 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 71)
  Conversation 23
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 10 September 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 72)
  Conversation 24
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 03 February 1987; Audiocassette (Cassette 73)
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 19 February 1987; Audiocassette (Cassette 74)
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 11 March 1987; Audiocassette (Cassette 75)
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, March 11, 1987; March 20, 1987; Audiocassette (Cassette 76)
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 19 May 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 77)
  Conversation 19: Tape 32
- 27 May 1986, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 78)
  Conversation 20: Tape 33
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 12 June 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 79)
  Conversation 21: Tape 34
- 18 June 1986, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 80)
  Conversation 22: Tape 35
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 08 September 1987; Audiocassette (Cassette 81)
  Conversation 23: Tape 36
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 10 September 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 82)
  Conversation 24: Tape 37
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 02 February 1987; Audiocassette (Cassette 83)
  Conversation 25: Tape 38
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, 19 February 1987; Audiocassette (Cassette 84)
  Conversation 26: Tape 39
- 11 March 1987, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 85)
  Conversation 27: Tape 40
- Conversations McMurrin and Newell, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 86)
  Conversation 28: Tape 40 and 41
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 1, 02 May 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 87)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 2, May 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 88)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 3, 03 May 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 89)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 4, 02 May 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 90)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 5, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 91)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 5, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 92)
  Tape 5 cont'd
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 6, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 93)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 7, 05 September 1984; Audiocassette (Cassette 94)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 8, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 95)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 9, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 96)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 10, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 97)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 11, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 98)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 12, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 99)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 13, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 100)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 14, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 101)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 15, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 102)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 16, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 103)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 17, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 104)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 18, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 105)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 19, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 106)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 20, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 107)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 21, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 108)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 22, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 109)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 23, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 110)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 24, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 111)
  Partial Tape
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 25, 04 February 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 112)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 26, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 113)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 27, 04 March 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 114)
  1961-1962 Commissionership
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 28, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 115)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 29, 08 April 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 116)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 30, 15 April 1986; Audiocassette (Cassette 117)
- McMurrin and Newell Conversation 31, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 118)
- Philosophical Roots of McMurrin's Theology: A Conversation with Sterling McMurrin and Jack Newell, August 1993; Audiocassette (Cassette 119)
- Philosophical Roots of McMurrin's Theology: A Conversation with Sterling McMurrin and Jack Newell, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 120)
- Philosophical Roots of McMurrin's Theology: A Conversation with Sterling McMurrin and Jack Newell, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 121)
- 1986 Sunstone Theological Symposium: 20 Year Retrospective on Contributions of Sterling McMurrin, Audiocassette (Cassette 122)
- At Kolob Cabin with Sterling and Natalie McMurring, Keith McMurring, and Linda and Jack Newell, 01 September 1993; Audiocassette (Cassette 123)
- Jack Newell Interviews, August 1993; Audiocassette (Cassette 124)
  With Sterling McMurrin at the Sunstone Symposium
- Jack Newell and Sterling McMurring continued, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 125)
- McMurrin, August 1993; Audiocassette (Cassette 126)
- Sterling McMurrin, August 1993; Audiocassette (Cassette 127)
- McMurrin-Newell Conversations 1-9, 1984-1987; Micro Floppy Disc (Disc 128)
  Tr. by Janice Crellin 581-0182
- McMurrin-Newell Conversations 10-20, 1984-1987; Micro Floppy Disc (Disc 129)
- McMurrin-Newell Conversations 21-33, 1984-1987; Micro Floppy Disc (Disc 130)
- McMurrin-Newell Conversations 34-36, 1984-1987; Micro Floppy Disc (Disc 131)
- McMurrin-Newell Conversations 37-41, undated; Micro Floppy Disc (Disc 132)
- McMurrin-Newell on KUED, 1984-1987; VHS videocassette (Cassette 133)
- University Portraits: Sterling McMurrin and L. Jackson Newell, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 134)
- Brigham Madsen on Almo Massacre of 1861, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 135)
  NPR
- John Wesley Powell River Journal: The Grand Canyon of the Colorado, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 136)
- Dad's Ultimate Cabin Travelin' Tape, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 137)
- Sterling McMurrin Memorial, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 138)
  Arthur Smith, Max Rogers, Brigham Madsen, David Gardiner. University of Utah Alumni House. Conducted by Patricia Hanna.
- Clam Lake Paper, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 139)
- Brigham Madsen on Almo, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 140)
- Brigham Madsen on Almo, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 141)
- Bertrand Russell Nobel Prize Acceptance 1950, 03 May 1950; Audiocassette (Cassette 142)
  Bertrand Russell, Sean O'Casey, David Ben-Gurion, and F.L. Wright
- Bertrand Russell Address on Receiving the Nobel Prize for Literature, 03 May 1950; Audiocassette (Cassette 143)
- Interview with Ivan L. Foisy, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 144)
- Jack Newell: University of Utah Library Education Program, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 145)
  continued, Tape 2: Side 3 of 4 and side 4 of 4
- Jack on KUER on Education, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 146)
- Jack's Speech, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 147)
- Newell-Midgley Debate: Part II, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 148)
- Newell-Midgley Debate: Part I, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 149)
- Jack Newell-Description of Creation of Library Education Program, 06 March 1997; Audiocassette (Cassette 150)
- Women's Conference Panel: Jack's Remarks, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 151)
- The Monday Nighters: Remembering Roald Campbell, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 152)
- The Moral Componenet of Religion, 1988; Audiocassette (Cassette 153)
  Lowell Bennion, Sunstone '88
- Family History, 1984, Audiocassette (Cassette 154)
  85th Birthday Party for Dat at Nutz Knob
- Ramona Adams, Bennion Study Group, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 155)
- This I Know and Education and the Charge to Subdue, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 156)
  by Elder Hugh B. Brown
- Portrait of a Prophet-Brigham Young, 1980; Audiocassette (Cassette 157)
  James Arrington(Vol. 1)
- God is the Gardner Here, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 158)
  Hugh B. Brown, Currant Bush Story
- Profile of Apostasy: Who Are the Bad Guys, Really?, 1993; Audiocassette (Cassette 159)
  Allen Roberts, L. Jackson Newell, resp
- Black Mormon, 06 April 1990; Audiocassette (Cassette 160)
  Aired on NPR's All Things Considered
- Sunstone Symposium IX: Plenary Session- Changing Family Roles, 1987; Audiocassette (Cassette 161)
  Tape 1
- Jack on Sunstone Panel, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 162)
- Devotional 1979, Audiocassette (Cassette 163)
  Bruce C. Hafen
- Jac at Tanners, June 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 164)
- Echo From Foothills, 1985; Audiocassette (Cassette 165)
  Jack 1985
- Echo From Foothills: The Obedience Dilemma, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 166)
  L. Jackson Newell
- The Purge, A Year Later, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 167)
  B.H. Roberts, University of Utah. With Lavina F. Anderson, Janice Allred, Jack Newell, Rod Decker and Fred Voros(moderator)
- Lord North, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 168)
- Sunstone Symposium III: Global Issues in Mormonism, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 169)
  L. Jackson Newell, Response: Reverend Jeffrey R. Silliman
- Portrait of a Prophet-Brigham Young, 1980; Audiocassette (Cassette 170)
  James Arrington(Vol 1.): Brigham on His Family
- Jack at Tanner Group, May 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 171)
  Jack Newell at Monday Nighters
- Isolation Policy Discussion, 03 September 2005; Audiocassette (Cassette 172)
- The Mormon Experience, May 1982; Audiocassette (Cassette 173)
  Mormon Men-U of U Conference
- Sunstone Symposium IX: Plenary Session-Changing Family Roles Part 2, 1987; Audiocassette (Cassette 174)
  Jack on changing family
- Scapegoats and Scarecrows in Our Town: What Do Christian Principles Require of Us?, 1993; Audiocassette (Cassette 175)
  L. Jackson Newell, J.D. Williams and Laurie DiPadova
- Scapegoats and Scarecrows in Our Town: What Do Christian Principles Require of Us?, 1993; Audiocassette (Cassette 176)
- Jack as Justin Morrill with Chas. Elliot, June 1971; Audiocassette (Cassette 177)
- Sunstone Symposium II: Personal Conscience and Priesthood Authority, 22 August 1980; Audiocassette (Cassette 178)
  L. Jackson Newell, Response by Stanley Kimball
- L. Jackson Newell: Introduction and Keynote Address, 08 September 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 179)
  Student Affairs retreat and Q and A Session
- Unlabeled, undated; Audiocassette (Cassette 180)
  Cassette does not contain any data.
- Jack on KUED-TV in March and on PBS-The Mormons in May, 31 March 1987; 13 May 1987; VHS videocassette (Cassette 181)
- Leonard Newell's Birthday Celebration, August 1986; VHS videocassette (Cassette 182)
  At Holiday Inn in Englewood, Ohio and 29 Granite Drive
- Jack on Wm. Perry, November 1987; VHS videocassette Poor quality audio (Cassette 183)
  Presentation at Grantsville High School on developing values, judgements, and committments.
- Wesey's 80th Birthday, September 1987; VHS videocassette (Cassette 184)
- Newell Family Album, 28 December 1985; VHS videocassette (Cassette 185)
- Bombings-Dads and Mom, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 186)
- Jack on Civil Dialogue, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 187)
- Jack Newell spot-KUED, undated; VHS videocassette (Cassette 188)
- University Portraits-O.C. Tanner, March 1990; VHS videocassette (Cassette 189)
- Jack on Singer Tragedy(01/28/1988)/Obert Tanner(06/24/1988), 28 January 1988; 24 June 1988; VHS videocassette (Cassette 190)
- David P. Gardner Lecture at Kingsbury Hall, 15 November 1990; VHS videocassette (Cassette 191)
- Ballet: Where Has It Come From and Were Is It Going, If Anywhere?, 31 January 1990; VHS videocassette (Cassette 192)
  Jacques d'Amboise, Recorded by CVS, IMS
- Dress Rehearsal-Games Cells Play, 01 February 1990; VHS videocassette (Cassette 193)
- Games Cells Play, 02 February 1990; VHS videocassette (Cassette 194)
- How College Does(And Doesn't) Affect Students, 1991/1992; VHS videocassette (Cassette 195)
  From the lecture series: The Art of College Teaching, Reconsidered. L. Jackson Newell as moderator. Pasvarella paper read by Newell. K.I. Spear as panelist
- Jack Newell Evening Lecture, 01 October 1990; VHS videocassette (Cassette 196)